### **IESSICA GONNELLA**

Middletown, CT 06457 C: 315-727-8993 ♦ jgonnella14@gmail.com

## Studio and Creative Graphics Producer

Emmy Award winning producer of broadcast television and motion graphics. Experienced in all facets of production including live event coverage, post-production, motion graphics and live action. Highly motivated media manager with a proven history of delivering award-winning content.

# **Work History**

## **Connecticut Public** – Hartford, CT

**Visuals Producer II,** 10/2021 to Present

Serve as a key leader with the Chief Content Officer and Visuals Director to strategize content for broadcast and digital platforms.

- Daily tasks include determining production schedules, facilitating communication between business groups and creative teams, identifying key art and media selects for online stories and managing deliverables while ensuring budget and timeline goals are met.
- Long-range responsibilities include leveraging content and resources to support all broadcast and digital initiatives, adapting workflows to meet evolving technology and content needs and prioritizing the goals set forth by the Chief Content Officer and Visuals Director in relation to project scope and narrative.

#### **ESPN** – Bristol, CT

### **Graphics Project Producer**, 08/2019 to 10/2021

Worked directly with the Director of Editorial Graphics Producers to oversee the development of studio graphic and animation needs across ESPN networks with an emphasis on touchscreen and virtual technologies.

- Daily tasks included facilitating quick turnaround graphic and animation requests, planning long-term graphic strategies, managing communication between show groups and creative teams, maintaining lists of deliverables with a focus on timelines and overseeing the deployment of graphic and animation packages from the studio perspective.
- Long-range responsibilities included sole oversight of interactive graphics focusing
  on touchscreen and virtual technologies. Duties included working with the
  technology and creative teams to develop and implement new technology into both
  studio and remote environments, managing product inventory, troubleshooting
  technological issues and training users on systems. Worked in close collaboration
  with sales teams to identify areas of partnership and ensure obligations were
  fulfilled.

### **Graphics Editorial Producer**, 08/2014 to 08/2019

Responsible for creating and supervising written, visual and statistical content for live broadcast.

Day-to-day tasks involved writing clear, concise content, often under tight deadlines
or breaking news scenarios during SportsCenter productions while communicating
graphic plans to show producer and director. Long-term responsibilities included

managing requests for new graphic elements and identifying branding opportunities for current shows as well as those in development.

### **BeIN Sports** - Miami, FL

## Managing Graphics Producer, 11/2013 to 08/2014

Responsible for on-air graphic content for all live programming for both English and Spanish broadcasts. Additional responsibilities included field producing, line producing, and overseeing graphic development.

#### Freelance - NY, NY

## **Motion Graphics Producer,** 02/2013 to 10/2013

Managed multiple projects simultaneously, with oversight from bid stage to final delivery. Additional responsibilities included coordinating teams of artists while managing budgets and actuals, creating and maintaining project schedules, and providing excellent customer service.

#### ESPN - Bristol, CT

### **Motion Graphics Producer**, 04/2011 to 02/2013

Worked with external production and design companies on the look of new programming as well as the rebranding of existing content. Responsible for all communication between vendor and client as well as development of deliverables lists and project schedules. Programs and packages worked on include 2014 SportsCenter rebrand, #Redes ESPN, Unite, and 2012 College Basketball rebrand.

## **Associate Producer,** 02/2006 to 04/2011

Performed various roles for live action shoots including line producing, script supervising, talent- managing, and post-production supervising. Also responsible for coordinating live on-air graphics and highlights for various sports with a focus on college basketball, soccer, and X Games events. Work included 2013 Macklemore College Basketball College Gameday tease, 2011 Nelly College Football Bowl Week campaign, 2010 FIFA World Cup, 2009 Jimmy V Classic tease, and 2009 Scripps Spelling Bee tease shoot.

#### **Education and Awards**

## Bachelor of Arts Communication Sciences, University of Connecticut - Storrs, CT

- 2x Emmy Winner
  - 2020 Daily Studio Show for SportsCenter
  - 2010 FIFA World Cup Spain/Netherlands Final (game broadcast)
- Promax BDA (Bronze) 2011 Nelly College Football Bowl Week Tease
- College Sports Media Award 2009 Connecticut/Syracuse 6 Overtime Tease
- Proficient in Spanish
- Division 1 Varsity Lacrosse